Matheus Chaves da Silva

Data: Brazilian

<u>(12)</u> 99775-6151 / (12) 98104-0486

matheussilvachaves19@gmail.com

Galo Branco - São José dos Campos - SP Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/matheuschaves1 Personal Website: https://chaves3.github.io/

Repository - chaves3/chaves3

GOAL.

Web Developer, Work in the Support area, Systems Analyst

PROFESSIONAL RESUME

Computer engineer with more than 3 years in the IT area. With experience in a multinational, working in large development projects, cost reduction and time management. I have solid knowledge in Web development, such as PHP, javascript and Python languages using MySQL database with the SQL Server language, among other technologies that I use to create high-level and valuable web applications. Experience

as support in computer formatting, handling networks, hardware, assembly and installation and computer maintenance. Expertise in installing and configuring operating systems. Skills in attention to detail, communication, interpersonal relationships, flexibility and agility.

Knowledge of technologies such as: PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Jquery, Bootstrap, Materialize, React (studying), Python, Visual Basic, MySql, SQL Server, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL and GIT

Results and Achievements:

- Implementation of web systems to improve the engineering laboratory sector;
- Development of a chemical product control system with registration, editing and deletion functionalities, generation of reports in PDF and Excel, and email alerts for expired products;
- Recognized in 1st place in the Conectados Project. Competing with more than 20 interns.

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

Graduação: Computer Engineering

Instituição: ETEP Esplanada

Período: 2018 - 2023

EXPERIENCE

Company: Autonomous
Office: Full stack developer
Period: 08/2023 – Current moment

- Responsible for writing clean and functional code on the front-end and back-end, testing and fixing errors or other coding problems, diagnosing, debugging and updating software;
- Data analysis;
- Development of web systems for initial customers;
- Implementation of both front-end and back-end;
- Use of the MySQL database;
- Programming in JavaScript and PHP languages.

Empresa: Aptiv - Multinational **Office: Apprentice in the IT area**

Office: IT Intern

Period: 02/2021 - 07/2023

- Provision of technical support for web and desktop systems throughout the factory;
- Development of web and desktop systems to optimize processes in all sectors;

- Use of Visual Basic, C# and PHP languages to develop customized solutions.
- Data analysis using Python, with the Anaconda and Jupyter libraries;
- Development of Python scripts using Spider for electrical tests;
- Use of JavaScript and PHP languages.
- Result: Implementation of web systems to improve the engineering laboratory sector;
- Result: Recognized in 1st place in the Conectados Project. Competing with more than 20 interns.

TECHNOLOGY

Knowledge of technologies such as: PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Jquery, Bootstrap, Materialize, React (studying), Python, Visual Basic, MySql, SQL Server, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL and GIT.

LANGUAGE

English – Intermediate to Advanced (Private Classes)

CERTIFICATIONS | COURSES

- JavaScript;
- PHP
- PYTHON;
- Visual Basic;
- SQL Server;
- MySql;
- Bootstrap;
- Materialize;
- Jquery;
- Angular;
- Vue Js;
- PHP Laravel;
- Python for Machine Learning and data science Didática Tech;
- Data scientist for beginners 2022 + 2 projects;
- Complete Web Development 2021 20 courses + 20 projects Udemy;
- Complete Web Master Front-end Course Danki Code;
- PHP Jedai Danki Code;
- Professional Course Administrative Assistant | Senai, 2022.

PROJECTS

1. Development of a chemical product control system with registration, editing and deletion features, generation of reports in PDF and Excel, and email alerts for expired products

Link: Sistema para controle de produtos químicos feito com PHP - YouTube

2. Recognized in 1st place in the Conectados Project.

All interns in the "Conectados" internship program propose to create a project that brings some improvement to their sector (mainly using one of the company's values: thinking like an owner). Among several presentations, my project (a software whose principle was the automation of some daily processes that previously generated internal and external problems) was one of the winners, coming in first place (the result was deliberated between the supervisors, I even received a simple tribute from supervisor Fabiano Pereira of Process Engineering on Linkedin).